Claudinei Callegari

Berlin, Germany cadicallegari@gmail.com Phone: +49 0152 3663 8091

Summary

I'm an enthusiastic software engineer graduated at Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Paraná - Brazil.

I'm always trying to find simple solutions for complex problems, I'm a big fan of automated tests, and I believe that collaborative and relaxed work environments walk together with productivity and creativity

I have worked with some technologies like C, Lua, and Java. In the last few years, I have been working with Ruby, Python, and especially with Go. I'm also interested in the functional paradigm that I have been studying with Scala and Clojure.

Most of my experience in the last years was working as a Data Engineer when I could help to develop and evolve a microservice architecture to scrape data from the internet, Develop and evolve a microservice architecture to run data pipelines and data science-related job

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana, BSc in Computer Science, December 2011.

Experience

FromAtoB

May 2019 - present

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Go, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, Dataflow, Bigquery, GCP;

Some of the data team responsibilities are data collection, transformation, storage, security, consumption in a variety of ways and monitoring.

To achieve that, the first step we had to take was extracting the data from the services, which were written in Go and Ruby, then publish to the pipeline.

Our pipelines are composed of cloud functions written in Go and dataflow jobs. We also have some services running inside Kubernetes cluster and Airflow scheduling Spark jobs and a bunch of dockerized jobs, most of them written in Python.

Neoway Business Solutions

May 2016 - Mar 2019

Software Developer

Main Technologies: Go, Python, Docker, Kubernetes;

As a member of the datasource team, I worked mainly with Python language to scrap data from the Internet. We created a framework to help us develop bots in a more quickly and reliable way. To support the tasks related to scraping data, we also had services written in Go.

As a member of the data analytics team, I worked with the same idea of creating a framework for the data scientists to develop their models in a more quickly and reliable way, having as the final artifact a variety of options like a python package or a spark job.

Inventsys: serial innovation

Fev 2016 - May 2016

Freelancer Android Developer

Main Technologies: Java, Android, REST, SQLite;

As a Freelance Java Android developer I helped the company to create an intelligent infrastructure management and urban service solutions. My focus was improving the features related to a device tracker using GPS. I also helped defining the REST API to connect server and devices, the application usability and unit testing.

DBA

 $Software\ Engineer$ - $Full\ Stack$

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Ruby, JavaScript, Java, Android;

As a team-member at DBA startup working part of the Parking Meter System project. I'm involved in all parts of the project, this means understand all clients requirements, web development using Ruby on Rails framework, modeling the database and testing the application. I'm also responsible for the frontend development, so hands on JavaScript (AngularJS) and HTML.

I also developed REST APIs to improve the communication with the devices, such as tablets and parking meters. The REST API was developed using Ruby/Grape framework. I've contributed to development of Android applications.

That Android applications were developed using some libs like RxAndroid, Retrofit, SqlBrite, Butterniffe, Dagger, Espresso and Robolectric.

Although I am a software engineer some times it is necessary working as sysadmins doing tasks like Linux and network administration, web servers management (Apache and nginx), log analyse, and so on.

Main tecnologies: Ruby, Rails framework, Android, Postgresql, Grape framework, Linux, Python, DBus, Amazon AWS, Dokku, REST.

Digitro

Sep 2012 - May 2013

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Windows, C, SDL;

Implement new features and maintenance of callcenter solution, acting mainly in backup area, using language C with SDL (Specification and Description Language).

Nexxera

Jul 2012 - Sep 2012

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux and Python;

Write scripts using Python, Java and closed tool to convert files "layouts" used to share informations between companies and banks, and vice versa.

Ahgora

Jan 2012 - Jul 2012

Jr Software Engineer

Main Technologies: C, Lua, Linux and Java(Android);

Implementation of comunication protocol with language C for ARM and 8051 processors. Development Android application to read RFIDs tags and comunicate to a REST service. Development some applications and modules using language Lua.

ITAI

May 2009 - Nov 2011

Trainee

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++ and Java;

Development with languages C, C++ e Java. Comunication between C and Java using SUN-RPC, JSON. Used Valgrind, Libxml2, Glib

More Info

• Linkedin: https://br.linkedin.com/in/cadicallegari

• Github: https://github.com/cadicallegari